{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Pick up the excavation where measurements are made in square metres for payment.", "opta": "Ordinary cuttings up to 1 m", "optb": "surface dressing up to 15 cm depths", "optc": "Surface excavation up to 30 cm depths", "optd": "Both (b) and (c)", "opte": "Both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The expected out turn of 2.5 cm cement concrete floor per manson per day", "opta": "2.5 sqm", "optb": "5.0 sqm", "optc": "7.5 sqm", "optd": "10 sqm", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A portion of an embankment having a uniform up-gradient 1 in 500 is circular with radius 1000 m of the centre line. It subtends 180\u00b0 at the centre. If the height of the bank is 1 m at the lower end, and side slopes 2:1, the earth work involved.", "opta": "26, 000 m3", "optb": "26, 500 m3", "optc": "27, 000 m3", "optd": "27, 500 m3", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The correct prismoidal formula for volume is", "opta": "D [first area + last area + \u2211 Even area + 2 \u2211 odd areas]", "optb": "[first area + last area + 4 \u2211 Even area + 2 \u2211 odd areas]", "optc": "[first area + last area + 2 \u2211 Even area + 4 \u2211 odd areas]", "optd": "[first area + last area + 2 \u2211 Even area + 4 \u2211 odd areas].", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The order of booking dimensions is", "opta": "Length, breadth, height", "optb": "Breadth, length, height", "optc": "Height, breadth, length", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As per Indian Standard Specifications, the peak discharge for domestic purposes per capita per minute, is taken", "opta": "1.80 litres for 5 to 10 users", "optb": "1.20 litres for 15 users", "optc": "1.35 for 20 users", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the item of work not included in the plinth area estimate", "opta": "Wall thickness", "optb": "Room area", "optc": "Verandah area", "optd": "W.C. area", "opte": "Courtyard area.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The bent up bars at a support resist the negative bending moment", "optb": "The bent up bars at a support resist the sharing force", "optc": "The bending of bars near supports is generally at 45\u00b0", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The brick work is measured in sq metre, in case of", "opta": "Honey comb brick work", "optb": "Brick flat soling", "optc": "Half brick walls or the partition", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Brick walls are measured in sq. m if the thickness of the wall is", "opta": "10 cm", "optb": "15 cm", "optc": "20 cm", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement in case of water supply.", "opta": "Pipes laid in trenches and pipes fixed to walls are measured separately", "optb": "Cutting through walls and floors are included with the item", "optc": "Pipes are classified according to their sizes and quality", "optd": "In laying pipes, the method of jointing and fixing is specifically specified", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In case of laying gullies, siphons, intercepting traps, the cost includes", "opta": "Setting and laying", "optb": "Bed concreting", "optc": "Connection to drains", "optd": "All of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In long and short wall method of estimation, the length of long wall is the centre to centre distance between the walls and", "opta": "breadth of the wall", "optb": "half breadth of wall on each side", "optc": "one fourth breadth of wall on each side", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The height of the sink of wash basin above floor level is kept", "opta": "60 cm", "optb": "70 cm", "optc": "75 cm to 80 cm", "optd": "80 cm", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "While preparing a detailed estimate", "opta": "Dimension should be measured correct to 0.01 m", "optb": "Area should be measured correct to 0.01 sqm", "optc": "Volume should be measured correct to O.Olcum", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the incorrect statement regarding a master trap from the following :", "opta": "It is provided in between the lower end of the house drain and the street sewer", "optb": "It is provided a cleaning eye at the top of the trap", "optc": "The height of fresh air inlet pipe fixed vertically with wall is 3 m", "optd": "The mica flap valve which opens inwards only, is fitted at the top of the inlet pipe", "opte": "The water seal is less than that of ordinary traps.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The concrete work for the following part of the building of specified thickness is measured in square metres", "opta": "Root slabs", "optb": "Floors", "optc": "D.P.C.", "optd": "Wall panels", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The estimated value of the work excluding the amount for contigencies, work charged establishment, tool and plants, is called work value", "optb": "The actual expenditure involved to complete a work including incidental, establishment and travelling charges, is called actual cost", "optc": "The formal acceptance by the administrative department for incurring an expenditure on the work, is called administrative approval", "optd": "The order of a competent authority sanctioning a properly detailed estimate of the cost of a work of construction or repair is called technical sanction", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The expected out turn of cement concrete 1 : 2 : 4 per mason per day is", "opta": "1.5 m3", "optb": "2.5 m3", "optc": "3.5 m3", "optd": "5.0 m3", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The area of the cross-section of a road fully in banking shown in the given figure, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The plinth area of a building not includes", "opta": "area of the walls at the floor level", "optb": "area of stair cover", "optc": "internal shaft for sanitary installations up to 2 sq m. in area", "optd": "lift and wall including landing", "opte": "area of cantilevered porch.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For 12 mm thick cement plastering 1 : 6 on 100 sq.m new brick work, the quantity of cement required, is", "opta": "0.200 m3", "optb": "0.247 m3", "optc": "0.274 m3", "optd": "0.295 m3", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The minimum width of a septic tank is taken", "opta": "70 cm", "optb": "75 cm", "optc": "80 cm", "optd": "90 cm", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The item of the brick structure measured in sq.m, is", "opta": "Reinforced brick work", "optb": "Broken glass coping", "optc": "Brick edging", "optd": "Brick work in arches.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The inspection pit or chamber is a manhole provided in a base drainage system", "opta": "at every change of direction", "optb": "at every change of gradient", "optc": "at every 30 m intervals", "optd": "at the point where vertical soil pipe joins the house drain", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the mid-section formula", "opta": "The mean depth is the average of depths of two consecutive sections", "optb": "The area of mid-sections is calculated by using mean depth", "optc": "The volume of the earth work is calculated by multiplying the mid-section area by the distance between the two sections", "optd": "The volume of the earth work is calculated by multiplying the mid-section area by the distance between the two original sections", "opte": "(a), (b) and (c) of the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The item of steel work which is measured in sq.m, is", "opta": "Collapsible gates", "optb": "Rolling shutters", "optc": "Steel doors", "optd": "Ventilators and glazing.", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The value of 'C' of Indian type W.C. shown in the given figure is :", "opta": "400 mm", "optb": "450 mm", "optc": "500 mm", "optd": "550 mm", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The area of a sloping surface of a protective embankment of mean height d, side slopes S : 1 and length L is", "opta": "d x d x s", "optb": "d2 x (ds)2", "optc": "L.D 1 + s2", "optd": "2 LD 1 + s2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the formation level of a highway has a uniform gradient for a particular length, and the ground is also having a longitudinal slope, the earthwork may be calculated by", "opta": "Mid-section formula", "optb": "Trapezoidal formula", "optc": "Prismoidal formula", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most reliable estiamte is", "opta": "Detailed estimate", "optb": "Preliminary estimate", "optc": "Plinth area estimate", "optd": "Cube rate estimate", "opte": "None of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The expected out turn of 12 mm plastering with cement mortar is", "opta": "2.5 sq m", "optb": "4.0 sq m", "optc": "6.0 sq m", "optd": "8.0 sq m", "opte": "10 sq m", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The main factor to be considered while preparing a detailed estimate, is", "opta": "Quantity of the materials", "optb": "Availability of materials", "optc": "Transportation of materials", "optd": "Location of site and local labour charges", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The damp proof course (D.P.C.) is measured in", "opta": "Cub.m", "optb": "Sq m", "optc": "Metres", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reduced levels of points, 30 metres apart along the longitudinal section of a road portion between chainages 5 and 9 are shown in the given figure. If there is a uniform up-gradient of the road 120 in 1, the chainage of the point with no filling or cutting is", "opta": "(6 + 15) chains", "optb": "(6 + 12) chains", "optc": "(6 + 18) chains", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The area is measured correct to the nearest", "opta": "0.01 sqm", "optb": "0.02 sqm", "optc": "0.03 sqm", "optd": "0.04 sqm", "opte": "0.05 sqm", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cost of fittings and their fixing is specified for the following sanitary fittings", "opta": "Water closets", "optb": "Flushing pipes", "optc": "Lavatary basins", "optd": "Sinks", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The volume is measured correct to the nearest", "opta": "0.01 cum", "optb": "0.02 cum", "optc": "0.03 cum", "optd": "0.04 cum", "opte": "0.05 sum", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The earth work of cutting in trenches or borrow pits in fairly uniform ground is measured with the help of average depths of the dead men", "optb": "The earth work in trenches or borrow pits in irregular ground is measured by taking the difference in levels before and after completion of work", "optc": "The earth work in trenches or borrow pits, where neither a nor b is feasible, are measured from the fillings after deduction of voids", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the item whose weight is added to the weight of respective item, is", "opta": "Cleats", "optb": "Brackets", "optc": "Bolts", "optd": "Distance separators", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The total length of a cranked bar through a distance (d) at 45\u00b0 in case of a beam of effective length L, is", "opta": "L + 0.42 d", "optb": "L + 2 x 0.42 d", "optc": "L - 0.42 d", "optd": "L - 2 x 0.4 d", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "While estimating a reinforced cement structure, the omitted cover of concrete is assumed", "opta": "at the end of reminforcing bar, not less than 25 mm or twice the diameter of the bar", "optb": "in thin slabs, 12 mm minimum or diameter of the bar whichever is more", "optc": "for reinforcing longitudinal bar in a beam 25 mm minimum or diameter of the largest bar which is more", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The excavation exceeding 1.5 m in width and 10 sq.m in plan area with a depth not exceeding 30 cm, is termed as", "opta": "Excavation", "optb": "Surface dressing", "optc": "Cutting", "optd": "Surface excavation.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the incorrect statement from the following:", "opta": "Dimensions are measured to the nearest 0.01 m", "optb": "Areas are measured to the nearest 0.01 sq.m", "optc": "Cubic contents are measured to the nearest 0.1 cm m", "optd": "Weights are measured to the nearest 0.001 tonnes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If tensile stress of a steel rod of diameter D is 1400 kg/cm2 and bond stress is 6 kg/cm2, the required bond length of the rod is", "opta": "30 D", "optb": "40 D", "optc": "50 D", "optd": "53 D", "opte": "59 D", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The measurement is not made in square metres in case of", "opta": "D.P.C. (Damp proof course)", "optb": "Form works", "optc": "Concrete Jaffries", "optd": "R.C. Chhajja.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "According to ISI method of measurement, the order of the sequence is", "opta": "Length, breadth, height", "optb": "Breadth, length, height", "optc": "Height, length, breadth", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The assumption on which the trapezoidal formula for volumes is based, is", "opta": "The end sections are parallel planes", "optb": "The mid-area of a pyramid is half the average area of the ends", "optc": "The volume of the prismoidal is over-es-timted and hence a prismoidal correction is applied", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cross-sections for a highway is taken at", "opta": "right angle to the centre line", "optb": "30 metres apart", "optc": "intermediate points having abrupt change in gradient", "optd": "the starting end points of the curves", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The detention period in a septic tank is assumed", "opta": "20 minutes", "optb": "25 minutes", "optc": "30 minutes", "optd": "40 minutes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}